<post>
    <turtle><![CDATA[
        :workflow a meta:Post ;
          dc:title "Workflow" ;
          dc:creator meta:me ;
          dc:issued "2013-05-10"^^xs:date ;
          meta:beginDate "2013-05-08" ;
          meta:subEntryOf :superiorautomaticdictionary .
        ]]></turtle>
    <html xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
        <h1>Workflow</h1>
        <p>There's no update mechanism in the client application; it's just for browsing.  See the <a>architecture</a></p>
        <p>Instead, I create posts in vim, and then have a command to POST them directly to the REST server.  Since I'm comfortable authoring XHTML and turtle, my documents are a smashup of the two, and there's a server-side transform on the REST server to turn the turtle into native MarkLogic triples.</p>
        <p>So copy any of the posts, edit the turtle section, and do some writing.  If you're interested in a term, surround it with &lt;a&gt;.  Next just POST the file you're working on with curl:</p>
        <pre>
curl --digest \\<br/>
    --user admin:admin \\<br/>
    -X POST \\<br/>
    -Hcontent-type:application/xml \\<br/>
    -d@"postname.xml" \\<br/>
    "http://localhost:8007/v1/documents?extension=.xml&amp;directory=/posts/&amp;transform=ingest&amp;collection=CURRENT"'
        </pre>
        <p>For this curl command, just replace the credentials and filename, if you've set up Richter as provided.  I've embedded a command in <a>vim</a> by putting the following into my vimrc file:</p>
        <pre>
command! SadPost call s:SendPost(expand("%")) <br/>
function! s:SendPost(buf) <br/>
let fname = a:buf <br/>
execute '!curl --digest --user admin:admin -X POST -Hcontent-type:application/xml -d@"' . fname . '" "http://localhost:8007/v1/documents?extension=.xml&amp;directory=/posts/&amp;transform=ingest&amp;collection=CURRENT"' <br/>
        endfunction
        </pre>
        <p>This POST command sends the file to the REST instance (using credentials that can write, unlike the client appserver).  Richter keeps old documents around, but only the latest one that you've posted with any given title will keep the CURRENT collection, and that's the collection that drives the client app.</p>
        <p>Image credit to Wikimedia http://commons.wikimedia.org/wiki/File:Pāhoehoe_Lava_flow.JPG</p>
        <img src="images/Lava_flow.jpg"/>
    </html>
</post>
